theoccidentalobserver.net 2019-11-29

# Privacy Policy – The Occidental Observer

### We Respect Your Privacy

Any personal information you provide to us, including and similar to: your name, address, telephone number and email address, will not be released, sold, or rented to any entities or individuals outside the core administrators of this site.

### Credit Card Details

_The Occidental Observer_ has several options for donations (see donate page) for all of our monthly or one-time donation transactions. Credit card and billing information is always handled on the 3rd-party processor server only — never here on TheOccidentalObserver.net — please check their policies for any privacy terms you need to be aware of.

### WordPress CMS

By default WordPress does not collect any personal data about visitors, and only collects the data shown on the User Profile screen from registered users. However some plugins may collect personal data. By default WordPress does not collect any analytics data. However, many web hosting accounts collect some anonymous analytics data. By default WordPress does not share any personal data with anyone. Our content servers and systems are all located inside the U.S. except for the cloud-based nameservers used for security which uses cloudservers in many places to detect attacks on the site. Security is all compliant with European data protection law which requires data about European residents which is transferred outside the European Union to be safeguarded to the same standards as if the data were in Europe. They have all contracts in place to safeguard all data of everyone who visits the site. We do not have access to those items or any collected data beyond basic analytics and speed data.

When visitors leave comments on this site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection and email address entered by you (not displayed publicly). If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue. Comments are mass-deleted on a regular basis which removes all data completely from the entire system.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you created an account there for your uploaded avatar image. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These cookies are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year unless you remove them from your browsers and temporary web files.

### External Sites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites most likely collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website. We are not responsible for the content of the many external web sites linked within our pages. You are advised to read the privacy policy of external sites before disclosing any personal information.

### Cookies

A “cookie” is a small text file that is placed in your browser which allows our site to recognize you each time you visit. Cookies themselves do not contain any personal information and are only used to enhance and personalize your experience while browsing our web site.

This site uses Google Analytics for site-wide statistics. You may opt out of their data storage (we’ve added the top software in order for you to do that), even though there is no recognizable data to us. We have never opted in to their regulated deeper analytics as we only use them to keep the site repaired and know if anyone is really visiting us. They gather IP addresses, browser type/app/operating system, etc., as all sites do which have statistics. We have looked at the data collected that is shown to us in their control panel, and nothing we see there identifies you personally. www.policies.google.com/technologies/cookies/ is where you will find all Analytics privacy information.

This site uses Jetpack by Automattic (WordPress) to handle our post and comment subscriptions so they retain the data you enter there yourself. Please contact us after you unsubscribe if you wish to verify your name/email data has been deleted from subscriptions. If you use an email address that is associated with Automattic’s (WordPress) Gravatar.com site, then it will show in the back end and if you leave a comment. We suggest you don’t use that email if don’t wish your image to show. People forget that. www.Automattic.com’s Privacy Policy will tell you all about what they collect (most of which only PHP programmers know). Visitor comments are checked through an automated spam detection service provided by WordPress/Automattic, Akismet. Data is pooled there to mitigate spam. Akismet collects information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect depends on how the User sets up Akismet for the Site, but typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).

This site uses a cloud-based DDOS attack protection system to assist on site speed, security, traffic mitigation, and general stats. They collect a great deal of data, but no personal information or identification. In order to be a security company, they have data and use it in ways we’ll never know. There is no way to avoid this service as they are the nameservers of the site itself (DNS).

### Remember The Risks Whenever You Use The Internet

While we do our very best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information that you might provide or is picked up from your browser for site stats (as even banks, credit agencies, insurance companies, government agencies and departments are broken into constantly) and you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any passwords or other account information. In addition, other web sites or services that may be accessible through our web site have separate data and privacy practices, independent of us, and therefore we disclaim any responsibility or liability for their policies or actions or losses.

There are security computer/device programs, such as Kaspersky Ultimate (has high ratings), that are able to guide you through setting up your browser(s) to match what you really want — then protect those settings quite aggressively.

Please contact those vendors and others directly if you have any questions about their privacy policies. Contact us for anything related to just this site, which does not use anything additional to present the site via WordPress.

Search-engine how to configure your browser (there are many) for the “privacy” that you would like to have. www.Youtube.com has instructional, short videos on How-To.

Finally, we reserve the right to change our privacy policy at any time (like everyone). We encourage you to check this page occasionally for the most current information. If you have any questions, concerns or suggestions about our privacy policy, please contact support at theoccidentalobserver dot net.

If you continue to use this site, you give consent to this Privacy Policy.  

Rev. 2 on 7/11/2018
